Guide to the Kramer family papers, 1939-2009.
Kramer family papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kramer family papers, 1939-2009.
3970
Kramer family.
5.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pictures, diaries, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include letters written to the Kramer family from Kevin Kramer while in Vienna. Also, pictures, letters, and diaries relating to Jeffrey A. Kramer's service aboard the U.S.S. Nimitz; papers concerning Samuel Kramer's World War II service; and Anne Gudis' and Samuel's war-time correspondence. Also, papers, research materials, notes, clippings, and correspondence relating to the history of the Ithaca Jewish Community.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Samuel Kramer of Ithaca, New York married Anne Gudis of Newark, New Jersey. Samuel served in the United States Army during World War II. Samuel and Anne had two sons, Kevin and Jeffrey, and a daughter, Michele. Kevin attended Cornell University and the Institute of European Studies in Vienna, Austria. Jeffrey earned a Master's Degree in Hospital Administration from Cornell University in 1973. He served aboard the U.S.S. Nimitz at the time of the aborted rescue mission of the U.S. hostages in Iran in 1980.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include letters written to the Kramer family from Kevin Kramer while in Vienna. Also, pictures, letters, and diaries relating to Jeffrey A. Kramer's service aboard the U.S.S. Nimitz; papers concerning Samuel Kramer's World War II service; and Anne Gudis' and Samuel's war-time correspondence. Also, papers, research materials, notes, clippings, and correspondence relating to the history of the Ithaca Jewish Community.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kramer family.; Kramer, Anne G.; Kramer, Jeffrey A.; Kramer, Kevin Leslie.; Kramer, Samuel J.; Nimitz (Ship).
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Iran Hostage Crisis, 1979-1981.; Jews--New York (State)--Ithaca.; World War, 1939-1945.; Family--Virginia--Virginia Beach.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photoprints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters to Anne Gudis from Samuel Kramer
  - Letters, May 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, June 5-19, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, June 22-29, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, July 2-10, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, July 11, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, January-February 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, March-April 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters, May-June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters, July-August 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters, September 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters, October 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters, November-December 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters, January 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters, February 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters, March 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters, April 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters, May-June 1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters, July 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letters, August 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters; also, photograph (possibly of Anne Gudis), September 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letter to Samuel Kramer from Anne Gudis
  - Letters, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters, January 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters, February 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters, March-April 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters, May-June 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letters, July-September 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Letters, October-December 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letters - drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Letters to Anne Gudis from various persons in response to her letter to Samuel Kramer, published in YANK, September 3, 1943
  - Letters, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
- Other material and correspondence
  - Anne Krammer's notes on the Ithaca Jewish Community (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cemetary records (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ithaca Jewish Community (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ithaca Jewish Community - research correspondence (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ithaca Jewish Community - notes (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Jewish history - papers by others (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings - Ithaca history (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "High above Cayuga's Waters - Jewish Life in Ithaca, NY" by Anne Kramer (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ithaca Jewish History – writings by Anne Kramer (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Clippings – Jewish Community, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: June Bell, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Jeff Kramer and Gene Dannen, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Glenside Monument – Michael Kramer, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Abe Gudis writings (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Temple Beth-El bulletin, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Sam and Abner Kramer, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sam and Abner Kramer's sisters (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letters from friends, etc. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Letters from Israel (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Typescript manuscript of autobiography (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Temple Beth El Building Program (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Temple Beth El (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - "Temple Beth El Bulletin", 1984-1993 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Anne Kramer's notes: the Ithaca Jewish Community (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ithaca Jewish Community (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Papers written by Anne Kramer (Box 2, Folder 28-31)
  - Notes and papers (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Temple Beth El, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Temple Beth El, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - History material (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Jewish history (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - U.S.S. Nimitz Passover Service, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Autobiography of Sam Kuntz, Ithaca restauranteur - his son founded Hal's Deli (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Newspaper clippings re: history (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Father's diary of trip to Israel, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Greeting cards, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Miscellany: letters, cards, 1887 unidentified photo, data on Morris Lubliner, 1887; 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Greeting cards, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 45-47)
  - Women and letter writing project, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Temple Beth-El Bulletin, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Papers re: Sam Kramer's military service in World War II (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Papers re: Jewish War Veterans of World War II (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (4) of Sam Kramer and other Jewish War Veterans (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sam Kramer - miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anne Kramer - misc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anne Kramer - Photograph album, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal papers of Sam and Anne Kramer (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nathan and Mary Kramer (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mary Kramer memorial book, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mary Kramer memorial book, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Abraham Gudis (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Michele/Vicki Kramer Lasker (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Letters of Kevin Kramer from the Institute of European Studies in Vienna, Austria, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Kevin Kramer from the John Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies in Bologna, Italy, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Personal papers of Kevin Kramer (Box 3, Folder 16-23)
  - Kevin Kramer's accident (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Jeffery Allan Kramer (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
  - Handbooks and newsgrams re: the U.S.S. Nimitz (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Yon Kippur services on the U.S.S. Nimitz (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Kramer house, Oak Avenue, Ithaca (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Kramer misc. (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
  - YANK, September 3, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - News clippings (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Tape recordings (4) sent to Anne and Sam Kramer by Jeffery, September 1979-September 1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Tape recording: reminiscences by Sam Kramer, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Temple Beth El correspondence, 1962-1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Guest book, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Appointment book, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards: 40th anniversary, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4-12)
  - Greeting cards and telegrams, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Greeting cards (Box 4, Folder 14-20)
  - Family greeting cards 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Thank you notes, 1978-1991 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Children's artworks and cards (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Children and grandchildren (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Jewish celebrations (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Children - programs, etc. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ithaca (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Greeting cards and thank you notes, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Greeting cards (Box 5, Folder 18-22)
  - Bar Mitzvah photographs (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified children and adults (possibly their teachers) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Notes on Jews, Hillel interview, article re Assunta Sullivan (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and newsletters, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Notes on Jews in American history (Box 5, Folder 28-30)
  - Jewish publications relating to history and genealogy, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Publications including 50th anniversary of Temple Beth-El [booklet] and article re Stephen S. Wise, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - High Above Cayuga's Waters, Alpha Bits, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Temple Beth-El Bulletin, other published items, Wall of Liberty Certificate (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Temple Beth-El Bulletin, correspondence, clippings, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Bas Mitzvah photographs, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Greeting cards, 50th anniversary, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Greeting cards, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Greeting cards and clippings, 1991-1995 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Cards to parents (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondences for the Jews in Small Towns Project, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Certificates of Appreciation, US Navy, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Celebration cards, 1962,1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4-12)
  - Graduation Commencement, University of Colorado, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Baccalaureate speech by Michael Lasker, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Letter from the White House, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Tulsa World newspaper article, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Marriage renewal certificate, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper supplement to the Virginian-Pilot, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, 1983 and undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Certificate of Honor (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with Scott Glass, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Artwork [rubbing] (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Temple Beth-El Bulletin, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 23-28)
  - Temple Beth-El Directory, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Copies of military records and clippings relating to his military service during World War II, 1991-2004 (Box 6, Folder 30-35)
  - Anne Kramer writings and materials, 1973-2000 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Samuel Kramer membership certificate, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Jeffrey A. Kramer military materials, 1981-1993 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Family news and updates, 1989-2006 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Samuel Kramer's certificate from the "Ordre National de la Legion D'Honneur", 2009 (Box 88)
  - Cemetery rubbings (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Rabbi Hoffman, tr. 1402a
  - Rabbi Hoffman, tr. 1403a